we'll leave it at that in fact on that
note let me also welcome on board gopal
balachandra and the CFO and chief risk
officer at icsa lombar General Insurance
gopal hi good morning good to have you
on the show it's been a relatively good
quarter for you in terms of the profit
growth of about almost 23% in a pandemic
year that too uh What's led to this
strong um profit and although the
combined ratio has actually increased to
101% as I understand it's been a bit res
in a p in a pandemic
year I think if you look at it from an
ICA Lombard standpoint uh uh not just
this quarter in general if you look at
the approach that we have been uh taking
for writing risk has been profitable
growth as an underlying theme and it's
the same approach that we have continued
even when you look at this particular
quarter and the point that you said that
this has been in that sense a difficult
year given that all of us has been
exposed to the pandemic even despite
that if you look at I so far as customer
preferences are concerned clearly the uh
the the placement of insurances of
customers are with companies which have
got relatively better balance sheet
solvency position and the underlying I
would say key performance metries and on
each of those parameters if you would
have seen for this particular quarter
that's gone by from a Topline standpoint
I think we were able to get to a
reasonable growth of almost about 9 to
10% thereabout contributed by across
lines of businesses and whether it is
commercial lines whether it is motor and
even to that extent even the health line
of business and the fact that I said
that uh from an approach standpoint we
have always looked at uh underwriting
the risk from a profitable growth theme
even in so far as the bottom line is
concerned I think we were able to be
reasonably uh comfortable so when you
look at not just the quarter generally
we Tred avoid talking to the in terms of
so far as quarterly performances are
concerned if you look at on an year to
date which is for the full year gone by
from a combined ratio standpoint you are
right I think we were kind of slightly
less than about 100% that's what we have
largely uh spoken about in terms of the
targeted uh combined ratio and even in
terms of I would say the profit after
tax growth uh it's been quite reasonable
and um the solvency is quite comfortable
at about 2.9 times as at the end of the
year and even Roe the return on equity
for us has been quite robust at about
21.7 % for the full
year right gopal you know you just
talked about the combined ratio and
we've seen a rise as well for you in
particular share with us some more color
on how the claims ratio has been so far
given the pandemic year and how has the
customer Behavior as well panned
out sure I think again that's a very
very valid uh question to ask uh I think
let's look at what's the year gone by uh
I mean uh while while we have been
talking about this U when you looked at
the first wave what did we what did we
see was clearly an increase in uh claim
so far as covid cases are concerned
understandably so but at the same time
when you look that across lines of
businesses some of the claim incidences
were significantly lower for example on
motor clearly because of the first wave
where this there was a severe lockdown
that happened in the country as a whole
we did see reduction in claim insurances
because the numbers of number of that
were flying on the road were far lower
even if you look at on the health side
while the covid cases saw a significant
surge the non-co health claims where
clearly one had seen a decline again
understandably so because customers were
apprehensive to go to a hospital to get
himself or herself treated but having
said that I think from an icsl Lombard
standpoint we always wanted to follow
the path of prudence and even in those
times in the initial couple of quarters
when the claim insurances were
relatively lower than what you would
have seen in a business as usual
scenario we continued with our approach
to providing for loss reserves and to
that extent we carried those loss
estimates keeping in mind the fact that
in the subsequent quarters there is
likely to be an increase in claim
incidence as in when the economic
activities will start to open up and
pretty much on expected lines when you
looked at quarter 3 and maybe early
quarter 4 we did see Resurgence of
activities happening in the country as a
whole and hence the approach to Prudence
when it cames to loss Reserve estimates
came in significantly
handy so while you do have strong
Capital ratios um would you have to
allocate more reserves towards the loss
reserves and what kind of a gross direct
premium income growth are you expecting
for IC Lombard Vis the rest of the
industry if you look at the year gone by
industry grew at about 5.2% we ended the
year with almost growth in line with the
industry but within segments I think
there have been uh uh lines of
businesses where we have significantly
had accretion of market share when you
look at for uh fy22 uh as I said at this
point of time obviously there's a lot of
uncertainties that is there but having
said that I think what we expect is from
an industry standpoint given the base
effect the industry should go in their
uh early teens uh between a 12 to 15%
range thereabout and from an ISL Lombard
standpoint our approach has been that if
the market remains sensible we would
want to see on the preferred segment
exhibiting growth Which is higher than
the market growth rate so that's a
stated objective from a growth
standpoint your first point on loss
reserves as I mentioned earlier our
approach to reserving has always been
following the path of prudence and to
that extent that's reflective of the
loss triangles that we disclose as a
part of our annual report or even as a
part of our results presentation as you
can see from the loss Reserve triangle
which gives information for 10 years
almost nine out of 10 years we have
actually seen a small amount of Reserve
releases which indicates the level of
prudence that we maintain when it comes
to estimation of loss reserves and hence
to that extent we believe we are
reasonably reserved uh in so far as um
claim insurances are
concerned now given that IC Lombard is
present across segments motor health and
fire Insurance Etc are you seeing any
signs of normalization in any of the
segments that you're currently present
in and which segments do you see gaining
market share and what is the competitive
intensity looking like in each of
these so let me kind of talk in the
context of what Isis Lombard is focusing
on so for example when you look at the
commercial lines as I said the
preference of customers is on Quality
Companies and given the balance sheet
strength and the solvency position and
the underwriting metries that we have
been able to achieve we are clearly
seeing a shift in market share happening
for us and that's something that We
Believe will kind of sustain even as we
get into fy22 so that's one on the motor
side of business what we are clearly
seeing is obviously given that there
have been low loss insurances for the
industry there is relatively heightened
levels of competitive intensity in the
market now the expectation is that one
would expect this things to continue for
some more time but the only factor is if
you look at the overall industry
combined ratios particularly for the
quarter three that's gone by quarter
four numbers are yet to be out for the
overall industry water 3 Industry
combined is still at about 119% which is
significantly adverse when you look at
relative to is Lombard's combined of
closer to 100% so hence the competitive
intensity will last for some time but
our expectation is that maybe somewhere
through the year we should expect
normalization to happen on the motor
line of business on health I think
clearly the runway for growth is
significant and that's one of our
preferred segments for IC Lombard
whether it is a retail inity or whether
it is a retail benefit segment I think
we are looking at very positive in so
far as uh growth opportunities in the
health segment is concerned and finally
I would say even onme that's again an
area of focus we see a lot of
opportunity in terms of growth when it
comes to the portfolio as
well right gopal lastly what's the
update on bharti AXA and also at an
industry level uh do you see
consolidation going forward will
inorganic growth be part of the overall
growth strategy in that sense
oh again that's a great question because
if you look at uh the the earlier point
that I made that the industry is
operating at a combined ratio in quarter
3 I'm not necessarily referring to
quarter one and Quarter Two because
those were periods where the loss
incidences were significantly lower for
the industry as a whole so quarter 3 is
more representative and quarter 4 when
the numbers are out I think we'll be
able to see the clear picture but
clearly the industry is still operating
as I said on a combined ratio of which
which is within that range of 118
119% given the strain that these players
are exhibiting and the fact that the
possibility of capital infusion becomes
incrementally limited given the
environment that all of us are operating
in there will definitely be room for
consolidation and it is in that context
where you have already seen some uh
transactions that have happened in the
market and even from an ICA Lombard
standpoint last year we did announce the
Dem merger of bti AA into ICA Lombard
that particular transaction is of course
subject to uh necessary approvals and at
this point of time we are ating
clearances from the NT and once the NT
clears we will go back to IID for the
scheme to be becoming effective but the
point is right I think the ability of
players to continue to be aggressive and
continue to lose let's say money on the
underwriting side could become limited
and therefore that by itself will open
up doors or opportunity in so far as
consolidation is concerned but at this
point of time from an i lomard
standpoint we would want to see this
particular transaction that we announced
last year to get through and then
obvious ly we will see if there is any
other uh transactions that come in the
process gopal great to have you in the
show thank you for taking the time out
and speaking with us today